JOSHUA ROBERTSON

SAS certified data science professional with excellent research and analytical skills. More than eight years of hands-on experience using predictive analytics and classical modeling techniques to create data insights for the finance industry. Able to work in teams and individually to complete projects on time and on budget.

2434 Third Road, San Antonio, TX 34567 j.robe rtson@email,com (789) 123-4560

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST

Sigma Systems, San Antonio, TX April 2016 - Present

DATA SCIENTIST

Gamma Finance, Dallas, TX July 2012-March 2016

- ♦ Collect, analyze and interpret raw data from various websites
- Combine analyses of massive data sets with theoretical knowledge to solve problems for finance industry
- Develop algorithms and analytical models using SAS, R and Hadoop to be able to predict sales outcomes with confidence
- Analyzed datasetsand communicated insights to business owners to assist with data-driven decision making
- Developed dashboards and reports that communicate a story and provide visualization of data in a way that can be best utilized by internal customers
- Evaluated business processes and recommend data science solutions to improve efficiency

EDUCATION

Master in Data Science and Analytics

University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK September 2011 - June 2012

Bachelor of Science of Information Technology

University of Tulsa, Tulsa, OK September 200? - June 2011

KEY SKILLS

- Data visu a I izatio n a n d communication
- · Machine learning
- SQL and Hadoop
- Risk analysis and problem solving abilities
- Software engineering experience

CERTIFICATIONS

- Senior Data Scientist, Data Science Council of America, 2018
- ♦ SAS Certification, 2019